# **KAREN ADKINS**

### Franklin, TN

Phone: 931-286-5637 | Email: kmadkins1129@outlook.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/karen-adkins-26a825246/ | Portfolio: https://astonishingcupcake-96fbfe.netlify.app

#### **SUMMARY**

Full-stack web developer with a focus in the MERN stack (MongoDb, Express, React, Node). Trained at Vanderbilt University coding boot camp and earned a certificate in full-stack web development. Strengths in critical thinking, teamwork, and problem solving. Previous experience as a dance instructor, nurse, bartender, server and manager.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Softwares/Platforms:** MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Apollo GraphQL, MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB Compass, Insomnia, Heroku, Github

Software Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

#### **PROJECTS**

### **AthleteTracker**

https://github.com/KarenAdkins84/GrandFinale

https://athletetracker.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Full stack client tracker app for personal trainer
- Role: Back-end development
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MongoDB, Express, Node.js, React, Apollo GraphQL

# **Blog About JavaScript**

https://github.com/KarenAdkins84/BlogStack

- Summary: Full stack blog app where users can create a profile with uploaded photos, create, edit and delete posts and comments.
- Role: Solo project with Udemy course
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Express, Node.js, MongoDB, and EJS

### ChefRosetta

https://github.com/KarenAdkins84/Recipes-Translator

https://ehamzapour.github.io/Recipes-Translator/

• Summary: App that allows user to search for recipes and have them translated into Spanish.

• Role: Front-end design

• Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, fetch API calls

### **EXPERIENCE**

Bartender 2022-2023

Condado Tacos Franklin, TN

Serve customers and make crafted cocktails in a fast-paced bar/restaurant. Excellent use of communication skills.

## Bartender/Server/Supervisor/Trainer

2019-2022

Ruby Sunshine Franklin, TN

Served customers and made cocktails in a high-energy fast-paced brunch restaurant. Promoted to trainer after a few months. Promoted to supervisor after one year.

# Bartender/Server/Supervisor/Trainer

2017-2022

Bricks Cafe Franklin, TN

Served customers, made cocktails and ran all FOH aspects of restaurant/bar. Promoted to manager after 3 months.

### **EDUCATION**

**Certificate: Full Stack Web Development** 

Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN 2022-2023

A 6-month intensive program focused on gaining skills in Full Stack Web Development, primarily JavaScript and the MERN stack.

**Degree: Associate of Applied Science- Nursing** 

2008 - 2011

Glen Oaks Community College, Centreville, MI